<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Honors Research]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Honors Research</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:52:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:52:16 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[CANVAS OF IDEAS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Have to check regulations on:Neighborhood scaleHow does the phasing impact the flora and fauna around the plots.
How are the neighboring residents affected?
How can we limit the inconveniences they face?Urban scalePlot scaleStructural &amp; Architectural imposed limits
Reusability of the materials we have. Crane positioning and how we work around that.
Leaving paths for construction vehicles ( we can't impede the construction works)
What are the regulations on going above a construction site
How does the phasing impact the traffic flow around the area (Maria has more insight on this)FoundartionsHelical pile anchorsOne way to use this system is to have concrete slabs acting as footings, along with helical anchors that are added to parts of the foundation that require more load bearing capacity.
<a href=".?query=tag:Research" class="tag colored-tag-research is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Research">#Research</a><br>
<a href=".?query=tag:Foundation" class="tag colored-tag-foundation is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Foundation">#Foundation</a>Helical anchors foundation › **Conclusions **<br><a class="internal-link" href="research/foundation/ballast-supported-foundations.html" target="_self">Ballast Supported Foundations</a>Edit overview<br>Helical anchors foundation › **Advantages **<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251214190742.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251214190742.png<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="GEM-STAGE-Factsheet-2021.pdf > page=1" data-href="GEM-STAGE-Factsheet-2021.pdf#page=1" href="media/pdf/gem-stage-factsheet-2021.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">GEM-STAGE-Factsheet-2021, page 1</a>The GEM-stage tower is a portable tower that is capable to provide the power needed for a full live show of a DJ. It can be fit in a container which can be carried by a semi-truck to the location and assembled there. Study the foundation implementation (precast concrete blocks)
Check connections and stability principles
Assembly &amp; transportation method
Ask about the weathering effects on the steel members/ connections
<br><a href=".?query=tag:Research" class="tag colored-tag-research is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Research">#Research</a><br>Gem-Stage tower (floor)<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251214213326.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251214213326.pngCore houses the electronics for the generation of solar energy. We could incorporate something similar if we have functions that require power. This way it doesn't impede the construction sites<br>Structure uses a very heavy core along with cables that anchor in submerged concrete pads to take horizontal loading<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251214214706.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251214214706.png
Regulatory Context and Classification
The structure's operation within the area covered by the Eindhoven Internationale Knoop XL project requires adherence to the Environment Buildings Decree (Bbl), particularly concerning temporary status and relocation.A. Temporary Structure ClassificationA "temporary structure" is defined as a structure with a maintenance period of no more than 15 years at the same location, making your 3-year plan compliant with this definition.• General Rules: The rules of Chapter 3 (Existing Structures) generally apply to the construction of a temporary structure, unless otherwise specified in Sections 4.2 to 4.7 (New Constructions),. The underlying assumption for structural and health requirements is that satisfying the rules for existing structures (Sections 3.2 to 3.7) is sufficient.• Specific Requirements (Chapter 4): Key rules from Chapter 4 that specifically apply to temporary structures include provisions related to:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;◦ Escape Routes and Fire Assistance: Articles 4.65 to 4.71 (course of escape routes) and Articles 4.84 and 4.85 (fire brigade lift/aid post) apply.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;◦ Ventilation and Flue Gas: The requirements for ventilation/flushing facility capacity (Articles 4.131 and 4.132) and rules regarding flue gas discharge/combustion air supply (Articles 4.135 to 4.141) apply.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;◦ Sustainability (Thermal): Articles 4.152 (thermal resistance), 4.153 (heat transfer coefficient), and 4.154 (air volume flow) apply, generally setting the minimum requirements at values specified in Table 4.148B,.B. Relocation RegulationsThe relocation of a temporary structure is considered the displacement of an existing structure,.• Rules for Displacement: When relocating an existing structure in an unchanged composition, the structure must comply with the rules of Chapter 3 (Existing Structures),. For a temporary structure, this rule remains applicable after relocation,.
Structural and Geotechnical Requirements
The structure's design must comply with the general design principles found in the Eurocodes, which inform the Bbl regulations.A. Structural Safety and Load CombinationsAll structures must be designed to withstand all forces during use and execution, and to prevent progressive collapse (disproportionate damage in the event of an accident),,.• Verification Basis: Verification of the ultimate limit state (ULS) is based on Eurocode (EN 1990),,,,.• Load Combinations: Structural non-failure verification involves using fundamental load combinations (normal use conditions),, and exceptional load combinations (e.g., resulting from fire, impact, or explosion),,.B. Optimal Foundations (Geotechnical Requirements)While the sources do not specify the single "optimal" foundation type (which depends on local soil conditions and logistics), they mandate the methodology for selecting suitable foundations and verifying their performance.• Geotechnical Design: Design must account for geotechnical aspects (soil, rock, groundwater) in accordance with Eurocode 7 (EN 1997),. Geotechnical investigations are required to establish the ground profile and strength/deformation properties.• Investigation Depth: The investigation depth must extend to all strata that will affect the project. For piles, this depth is typically down to a level below the lowest point of the pile base,.• Bearing Resistance and Settlement: The bearing resistance and settlement of spread foundations may be derived using:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;◦ Semi-empirical or analytical methods from Cone Penetration Test (CPT) results.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;◦ Standard Penetration Test (SPT) or Dynamic Probing (DP) results in coarse soil, provided local experience or reliable correlations are used,Ballasted supported foundationThis type of foundation relies on weight to provide resistance against uplift and lateral forces.
<br>Ballasted systems (non penetrating)- this type of foundation relies solely on weight to resist against forces. The most common materials are concrete blocks, like the system used in <a data-href="Gem-Stage tower (floor)" href="research/gem-stage-tower-(floor).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gem-Stage tower (floor)</a>. This is the most common method and probably the most cost efficient. Steel baskets filled with agregate, and containers filled with water/concerte are also used. These are best used when penetration is prohibited or impractical (this might be relevant to us depending on what the municipality tells us the construction sites will be).
Failure modes-Ground failure, since this foundation doesn't penetrate the ground, it relies on distributing the force over weak soil like mud or peat.
Concrete based footings- More traditional approach, this casts or drills piles into the ground for heavy load bearing. This might be a good option provided we can remove the foundation and reuse it again (if the loads call for such heavy foundation elements)
Submerged concrete blocks with ballast above. We could have big concrete blocks that are underground at around -1.000mm. The primary failure mode of this method would be shear failure of the slab. This, however can be mitigated by increasing the number of contact points to the ground thus decreasing the load on each one, adding rebar and changing dimensions.<br>
<a href=".?query=tag:Research" class="tag colored-tag-research is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Research">#Research</a><br>
<a href=".?query=tag:Foundation" class="tag colored-tag-foundation is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Foundation">#Foundation</a>
Ballast Supported Foundations<br>Look into starwin and their developed method (still this might need submerging by -0.500mm<img src="media/images/img-15-12-2025-120629098.png" draggable="false" target="_self">IMG-15-12-2025-120629098.png<img src="media/images/img-15-12-2025-120548680.png" draggable="false" target="_self">IMG-15-12-2025-120548680.png<img src="media/images/img-15-12-2025-120418416.png" draggable="false" target="_self">IMG-15-12-2025-120418416.png<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251214215500.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251214215500.png<img src="media/images/gemini_generated_image_hbccjnhbccjnhbcc.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Gemini_Generated_Image_hbccjnhbccjnhbcc.png
Rules for temporary structures are less strict as we can use the existing building protocols instead of the new construction ones
Foundations should be made with precast concrete slabs instead of pouring piles (See Floor project)
Load combinations along with 3D wind patterns have to be considered. ( less of an issue if we go for the small wildlife variant as the structures are much smaller)
Dynamics of users have to be taken into account&gt; steel doesn't dampen vibrations well and it can cause resonance which weakens the structure
Possible limitation of non penetrating systems is that I have mainly found them to be implemented in solar pannel arrays
Oslo Opera House
TU Delft Library
Ewha womans university<br>
<a data-href="4. The High line" href="research/second-ground-architectural-works/4.-the-high-line.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">4. The High line</a><br>
<a href=".?query=tag:Research" class="tag colored-tag-research is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Research">#Research</a>
Second Ground architectural works<br>The high line<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251219005135.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251219005135.png<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251219004012.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251219004012.png<img src="media/images/pasted-image-20251219003844.png" draggable="false" target="_self">Pasted image 20251219003844.png]]></description><link>canvas-of-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">CANVAS OF IDEAS.canvas</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:27:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>